<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Steffen Fritz</title>
    <link>https://fritz.wtf/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Steffen Fritz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>de-de</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 17:00:47 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fritz.wtf/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The NSRL For Hackers</title>
      <link>https://fritz.wtf/posts/nsrl/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 17:00:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritz.wtf/posts/nsrl/</guid>
      <description>A short article I wrote for 2600 - The Hacker Quarterly. It is about the National Software Reference Library and what they and you can do with it.
2600 is going through tough times right now and I would appreciate it very much if you would buy the magazine, https://store.2600.com/collections/pdf-downloads
The NSRL For Hackers First published in 2600, 37:3
The National Software Reference Library (NSRL) is something you probably never heard of, although it is one of the largest software collections in the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pacaudit discontinued</title>
      <link>https://fritz.wtf/posts/pacaudit_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 22:40:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritz.wtf/posts/pacaudit_6/</guid>
      <description>Pacaudit had a bug that could cause wrong results to be displayed. Since the tool was intended to serve security and I have no time to fix it, I discontinued it and deleted the AUR. The Github repo is archived. Please use arch-audit from the comunity repo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sao Tome - Cemetery Of Lost Images</title>
      <link>https://fritz.wtf/posts/saotome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 13:12:42 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritz.wtf/posts/saotome/</guid>
      <description>Roaming around the web and Google maps in the Covid-19-lockdown I noticed there is a special place west of Sao Tome. There are a lot of pictures in the Gulf of Guniea, in the triangle of Sao Tome, St. Helena and Ascension. These pictures don&amp;rsquo;t belong there. I found no other place in Google maps where are images wrongly placed by geo tags in this quantity.
Use street view on the following location link:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pacaudit - v.1.1.2</title>
      <link>https://fritz.wtf/posts/pacaudit_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2020 10:40:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritz.wtf/posts/pacaudit_5/</guid>
      <description>pacaudit v1.1.2 was released, install it via trizen or any other AUR pkg manager and read the man page.
trizen -S pacaudit man pacaudit  pacaudit has a alpm-hook (since v1.1.1), so you will get a warning if you try to install a vulnerable package. v1.1.2 checks if security.archlinux.org is up and running. If not a message is shown and pacaudit returns without checking local packages.
Comments on AUR, github or via email are highly appreciated!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pacaudit - v.1.1.0</title>
      <link>https://fritz.wtf/posts/pacaudit_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2019 22:40:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritz.wtf/posts/pacaudit_4/</guid>
      <description>pacaudit v1.1.0 is ready, install it via trizen or any other AUR pkg manager and read the man page.
trizen -S pacaudit man pacaudit  There is the idea that pacaudit could be a pacman hook to warn the user when she tries to install a vulnerable package. If you&amp;rsquo;d like to help with this task, checkout the issue page on github.
Comments on AUR, github or via email are highly appreciated!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EOL of my XMPP service</title>
      <link>https://fritz.wtf/posts/xmpp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 22:40:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritz.wtf/posts/xmpp/</guid>
      <description>After years of not using it I will stop my xmpp/jabber service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gobagit - A tool to work with the BagIt format </title>
      <link>https://fritz.wtf/posts/gobagit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2019 11:07:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritz.wtf/posts/gobagit/</guid>
      <description>gobagit is a command line tool and golang library to work with the BagIt format I am writing currently.
I really like the bagit format because it is simple, a standard (RFC 8493) and widely used. gobagit is available in version 0.2.0 and under heavy development, check the dev branch.
I&amp;rsquo;d like to get some feedback, so drop me an issue or star on github.
https://github.com/steffenfritz/bagit  You don&amp;rsquo;t have to build the tool yourself, just download a pre-built from the release page</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pacaudit - v.1.0.1</title>
      <link>https://fritz.wtf/posts/pacaudit_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 22:40:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritz.wtf/posts/pacaudit_3/</guid>
      <description>pacaudit v1.0.1 is ready, install it via trizen and read the man page.
trizen -S pacaudit  Comments on AUR, github or via email are highly appreciated!
Github</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mxcheck - a smtpd checker</title>
      <link>https://fritz.wtf/posts/mxcheck/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 11:07:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritz.wtf/posts/mxcheck/</guid>
      <description>I needed a tool to check mail servers for open relaying and proper dns settings. There are several web sites providing such services, but I like my tools locally if possible.
As I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find such a tool, I wrote one. You can find it on Github:
https://github.com/steffenfritz/mxcheck  With golang installed you can go get it with
go get github.com/steffenfritz/mxcheck  Usage is simple:
./mxcheck -t TARGETHOST  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>roy is in the AUR - create custom signature files for siegfried</title>
      <link>https://fritz.wtf/posts/roy_aur/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 21:35:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritz.wtf/posts/roy_aur/</guid>
      <description>I wrote a PKGBUILD file for roy. With this handy tool you can create custom signature files for siegfried, the &amp;ldquo;signature-based file format identification tool.
Install it on Arch Linux with
yaourt -S roy
roy and siegfried are developed by Richard Lehane. For more info check http://www.itforarchivists.com/siegfried</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>siegfried - a signature-based file format identification tool</title>
      <link>https://fritz.wtf/posts/siegfried_aur/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2017 13:12:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritz.wtf/posts/siegfried_aur/</guid>
      <description>I wrote a PKGBUILD file for siegfried, the &amp;ldquo;signature-based file format identification tool, implementing the National Archives UK&amp;rsquo;s PRONOM file format signatures and freedesktop.org&amp;rsquo;s MIME-info file format signatures
Install it on Arch Linux with
yaourt -S siegfried
The package is called siegfried, the binary sf. After the installation run sf -update to fetch a recent version of the signature database.
Siegfried is developed by Richard Lehane. For more info check http://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pacaudit - v.0.3.1</title>
      <link>https://fritz.wtf/posts/pacaudit_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 23:49:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritz.wtf/posts/pacaudit_2/</guid>
      <description>pacaudit v0.3.1 is ready, install it via yaourt.
Comments on AUR, github or via email are highly appreciated!
Github</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pacaudit - v.0.3.0-DEV</title>
      <link>https://fritz.wtf/posts/pacaudit_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 23:49:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritz.wtf/posts/pacaudit_1/</guid>
      <description>pacaudit v0.3.0 is ready and needs some testing. Btw, there are some changes.
If pacaudit is executed without flags, it just prints the number of vulnerable packages installed.
If executed with -v in verbose mode, it prints the names of the packages, the severities and all CVE.
If executed with -n in Nagios mode, it just prints OK, WARNING or CRITICAL.
A man page is added. Read it with groff -man -Tascii pacaudit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pacaudit - a package audit for Arch Linux</title>
      <link>https://fritz.wtf/posts/pacaudit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2017 13:12:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritz.wtf/posts/pacaudit/</guid>
      <description>I wrote a little, but useful helper. pacaudit checks installed packages against known vulnerabilities listed on https://security.archlinux.org. You should run it after an update because we don&amp;rsquo;t check for packages that are fixed. It would be no problem to check against all known vulnerabilities, just change the source URL in the code (see the github link), yet it makes no sense to me for a rolling release distribution.
You can install it with</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Siegfried ported to FreeBSD</title>
      <link>https://fritz.wtf/posts/siegfried_port/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2017 21:35:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritz.wtf/posts/siegfried_port/</guid>
      <description>Siegfried is in the FreeBSD ports.
Freshports</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rewriting History - with warc files and internet archives</title>
      <link>https://fritz.wtf/posts/rewrhist/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2016 22:18:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritz.wtf/posts/rewrhist/</guid>
      <description>Not a paper, but a short article. First published in 2600 - The Hacker Quarterly.
Download pdf</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XI HOPE!</title>
      <link>https://fritz.wtf/posts/hopeconf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2016 22:18:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritz.wtf/posts/hopeconf/</guid>
      <description>All talks will be streamed at https://www.hope.net</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KNMDI - Computertechnik: Folien, Images, Screencasts</title>
      <link>https://fritz.wtf/posts/hinweis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2016 22:18:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritz.wtf/posts/hinweis/</guid>
      <description>Alle Unterlagen und Testdaten finden sich hier.
Bei Fragen: Fragen. -&amp;gt; steffen AT fritz.wtf</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KNMDI - Computertechnik: Test-Image Sitzung 27.6.2016</title>
      <link>https://fritz.wtf/posts/usbimg/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2016 22:18:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritz.wtf/posts/usbimg/</guid>
      <description>  Image des USB-Sticks: https://fritz.wtf/sitzung_1_usb.img.zip
  Image erstellen unter Linux mit dd:
dd if=/dev/sdb of=/sitzung_1_usb.img
  Hashsumme erstellen mit sha1
sha1 sitzung_1_usb.img &amp;gt; hash.sha1
  Image mounten
file -s sitzung_1_usb.img
parted sitzung_1_usb.img; unit; B; print
sudo mount -o loop,ro,offset=1048576 sitzung_1_usb.img /mnt/image
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacker Magazines - An Overview</title>
      <link>https://fritz.wtf/posts/hackermag/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2016 13:42:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritz.wtf/posts/hackermag/</guid>
      <description>When you&amp;rsquo;re interested in infosec, you are probably looking for some good hacking and infosec magazines. Here is an overview of zines I read on a regular basis.
2600 - The Hacker Quarterly   Founded: 1984
  Language: English
  Latest: 2016-06
  Level: beginner, advanced
  Frequency: quarterly
  Topics: implementation errors, url guessing, politics, activism
  URL: http://2600.com
  Price print: $27 p.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Siegfried on FreeBSD</title>
      <link>https://fritz.wtf/posts/siegfried_freebsd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 21:04:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritz.wtf/posts/siegfried_freebsd/</guid>
      <description>Last weekend I ported siegfried to FreeBSD. Siegfried is an advanced file identification tool, using the National Archives UK&amp;rsquo;s PRONOM and freedesktop&amp;rsquo;s MIME-info file format signatures. It&amp;rsquo;s written in Go and compared to other file id tools pretty fast.
The port can be found on github, it is waiting to be added to the ports tree.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Irgendwas mit DH - Mai 2016 - II</title>
      <link>https://fritz.wtf/posts/dh_mai_2016_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2016 22:05:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritz.wtf/posts/dh_mai_2016_1/</guid>
      <description>DH Box – Digital Humanities Virtual Workbench : &amp;ldquo;Setting up an environment for digital humanities computational work can be time-consuming and difficult. DH Box addresses this problem by streamlining installation processes and providing a digital humanities laboratory in the cloud through simple sign-in via a web browser&amp;rdquo; : http://dhbox.org/
  A blog post on dhbox.org by Tony Hirst : ouseful.info
  KB Research : Dataset KBK-1M containing 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DigiPress - Mai 2016</title>
      <link>https://fritz.wtf/posts/digipress_mai_2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2016 22:05:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritz.wtf/posts/digipress_mai_2016/</guid>
      <description>News from the digital preservation community
  Euan Cochrane wrote a nice tool for the identification of floppy disk formats from kryoflux stream files: github
  ffmprovisr - Making FFmpeg Easier: github
  Tracking versions with PAV: The PAV ontology specializes the W3C PROV-O standard to give a lightweight approach to recording details about a resource, giving its Provenance, Authorship and Versioning. https://practicalprovenance.wordpress.com
  Migrating Files to Preservation Formats - Theory: http://archival-integration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Archivierbarkeit von Webobjekten</title>
      <link>https://fritz.wtf/posts/praxisreport/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2016 22:18:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritz.wtf/posts/praxisreport/</guid>
      <description>My article Praxisreport: Verfahren zur Evaluierung der Archivierbarkeit von Webobjekten is free available:
Praxisreport: Verfahren zur Evaluierung der Archivierbarkeit von Webobjekten</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Irgendwas mit DH - Mai 2016</title>
      <link>https://fritz.wtf/posts/dh_mai_2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2016 22:05:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritz.wtf/posts/dh_mai_2016/</guid>
      <description>LIBREAS – Call for Papers: Post-Digital Humanities aus bibliotheks- und informationswissenschaftlicher Sicht : https://libreas.wordpress.com
  Neoliberal Tools (and Archives): A Political History of Digital Humanities : https://lareviewofbooks.org
  Response to “Neoliberal Tools: A Political History of Digital Humanities” : http://alisonhedley.com
  Tagungsbericht Digitale Daten in den Geisteswissenschaften. Interdisziplinäre Perspektiven für semantische und strukturelle Analysen : www.hsozkult.de
  Interview Bildungsmaterialien bereitstellen und entwickeln über Github : www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conference: DigiBiz</title>
      <link>https://fritz.wtf/posts/digibiz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2016 09:55:34 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritz.wtf/posts/digibiz/</guid>
      <description>How will business histories be written from digital records?
&amp;ldquo;The National Records of Scotland, in collaboration with the University of Glasgow’s Centre for Business History in Scotland (CBHS), is hosting a one day conference on the theme of using digital records for business history research. The conference will be held in Edinburgh on Monday 9th May 2016, and is an exciting opportunity for archivists, historians and technical experts with an interest in business records to meet and discuss the challenges and opportunities presented by the shift of records from the physical to the digital.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DigiPress - April 2016</title>
      <link>https://fritz.wtf/posts/digipres_april_2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2016 13:12:12 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritz.wtf/posts/digipres_april_2016/</guid>
      <description>News from the digital preservation community
  W3C - Packaging on the Web: This document describes an approach for creating packages of files for use on the web. The approach is to package them using a new application/package media type
  The Archive.org v1 API specification: on Github
  warcprox - WARC writing MITM HTTP/S proxy: Fork on Github
  Do Multiple Listeners to the Public Twitter Sample Stream Receive the Same Tweets?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open365 - an open source Office365 alternative</title>
      <link>https://fritz.wtf/posts/open365/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2016 13:12:12 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritz.wtf/posts/open365/</guid>
      <description>eyeOS, bought by Telefonica in 2014, is developing an open source alternative to Office365. It is called Open365 - not that creative. Nevertheless, it looks good, it feels good and there are sync clients for Linux, OS X and Windows. Open365 provides LibreOffice Writer, Impress and Calc, a calendar and an address book.
In the next few weeks eyeOS will provide a download and therefore the possibility to have Open365 on premises.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>goml - a machine learning library for Go</title>
      <link>https://fritz.wtf/posts/goml/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 13:12:12 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritz.wtf/posts/goml/</guid>
      <description>When learning a new programming language, you need a project. Here is mine for learning Go. It&amp;rsquo;s is called goml and one day it will be a machine learning library. Pull requests and comments are highly welcome!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Iceland 2016</title>
      <link>https://fritz.wtf/posts/iceland/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2016 13:12:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritz.wtf/posts/iceland/</guid>
      <description>In april I visited Iceland and took some pictures. You can find them here.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
